Cristina Marban                                                            

15 Technical Writing Job Ads


1. Technical Writer / Proposal Writer
C Squared Systems Manchester, NH

Posted 22 days ago in Marketing/PR

We are seeking a full time Technical Writer / Proposal Writer for our SitePortal offering and C² Systems services. This is a great opportunity to join a dynamic company with exposure to all types of telecommunications and network management companies in a rapidly expanding field. This position is based from C Squared Systems office in Auburn, New Hampshire.

Key Responsibilities:

    Coordinate and respond to customer Request for Proposals (RFPs)

    Drive the RFP process to ensure content is accurate and deadlines are met

    Research industry RFPs to reach new markets and expand customer base

    Create and manage content library for RFP responses

    Develop and maintain product sales sheets and brochures, ensuring current & accurate content

    Help produce and distribute product update release announcements, user advisories, and press releases

    Assist with updates to company web site: copy, announcements, blog and software version updates

    Help create and update technical content and documentation

    Creative writing, including white papers, sales sheets, brochures

    Provide research and reports based on information collected such as trends, competition, new products, and pricing

Skills/Qualifications:

    Bachelor’s degree and/or 2-5+ years RFP response experience, copywriting, client services experience

    Strong writing skills

    Proficient at creating presentations with PowerPoint with eye for professional, aesthetically pleasing, and polished product

    Working knowledge of Excel and Outlook

    Knowledge of GoToMeeting/Webinar or similar webinar platform

Employment Type: Full-Time
About C Squared Systems:

C2 Systems is a Radio Frequency Engineering, Consulting, and Software Development company providing radio frequency analysis, design, activation and integration services, as well as custom software development for the voice and data wireless communications industry. We pride ourselves on being highly respected with many repeat customers willing to provide confident references. As leaders in our industry, we can offer our employees challenging opportunities where each person can make a difference and be recognized for their contributions.


         
  
2.	Job # 	8646BR
	Position Title 	Technical Editor and Writer
	Job Category 	Cyber
	City 	San Antonio
	State 	TX
	Country 	UNITED STATES
Why Engility? 	Join Engility and see your engineering and technology expertise help address the nation’s most pressing and complex challenges. Engility works with our customers on missions that strengthen security and safety and protect the basic values of our society.
Job Responsibilities 	 .

· Researches and compiles technical data for use in documents or sections of documents such as manuals, procedures, and specifications (Current/Active-Top Secret/SCI clearance required)

· Works with off-site print plant to publish and deliver hard-copy documentation

· Analyzes requirements of project to determine types of publications needed

· Maintains ongoing work log of mission-critical reports and plans

· Obtains data from independent observation, consultation with technical staff members or study of published materials and drawings

· Collaborates with technical writing and documentation development team members to share work load and ensure on-time delivery

· Ensures accuracy and completeness of technical documentation

· Writes and edits functional descriptions, system specifications, special reports, and any other customer deliverables and documents
Provides expertise in document generation and document storage and maintenance
Qualifications 	

    Bachelor’s Degree in Communications, English, or a related subject
    Two years’ experience as a writer and editor
    Expert knowledge of MS Word, Excel, and PowerPoint
    Experience in writing and editing technical publications
    Some knowledge of Adobe Acrobat and MS Visio
    In-depth knowledge of APA style
    Excellent interpersonal skills
    Adaptability to rapidly changing priorities
    Ability to work independently with limited direction
    Ability to work a flexible schedule is required
    Knowledge of basic Information Technology terminology
    IAT Level II desired, not required

About TASC 	Engility Corporation is proud to be an Affirmative Action/Equal Opportunity Employer. We provide equal employment opportunity for all persons, in all facets of employment. Engility Corporation maintains a drug-free workplace and performs pre-employment substance abuse testing and background checks. If you are a qualified disabled veteran or individual with a disability and need a reasonable accommodation to use or access our online system, please contact our Human Resources department via the Contact Us page.
Position Type 	Full Time
Sector 	Naval and AF
Division 	Air Force
Customer Market 	US Air Force
Minimum Clearance 	TS/SCI
JBC 	SF: CJ
SF: LI
SF: MON


3. Job Summary

Company
    Enterprise Products Company
Location
    Houston, TX 77001
Industries
    Energy and Utilities
Job Type
    Full Time
    Employee
Education Level
    High School or equivalent
Career Level
    Manager (Manager/​Supervisor of Staff)
Job Reference Code
    0006J3M21
Contact Information
    Enterprise Products Company 
    Houston, TX 77001

Specialist, Technical Writer
About the Job


Enterprise Products Partners L.​P.​ is one of the largest publicly traded partnerships and a leading North American provider of energy services to producers and consumers of natural gas, natural gas liquids, crude oil, refined products and petrochemicals.​ Headquartered in Houston, Texas, Enterprise Products is ranked 59th on the FORTUNE 500 and has approximately 6,900 employees.​ Enterprise’s large, integrated portfolio of operationally and geographically diverse assets, highlighted by its approximately 49,000-mile pipeline network, serves as the foundation for organic growth opportunities.​ As a provider of largely fee-based services, Enterprise is less susceptible to commodity price fluctuations and offers stable sources of revenue.​ The partnership’s service offerings include pipeline transportation and gathering, processing, storage, fractionation, terminalling, import/​export capabilities and marketing.​ Enterprise also has a marine transportation business that operates primarily on the United States inland and Intracoastal Waterway systems and in the Gulf of Mexico.​ Additionally, energy professionals are discovering rewarding opportunities with Enterprise Products by putting their skills to work in exciting new growth areas, developing markets and pursuing innovative solutions for meeting the needs of customers and promote energy security for the country.​


Make the most of your talents in a fast-paced environment driven by people who strive for achievement.​ Enjoy corporate strength, stability, and a rewarding career at a growing industry-leading and diverse operating company with a track record for success.​ Tap into the professional possibilities of Enterprise Products Company.​

The Technical Writer Specialist designs, writes, publishes, maintains, and provides translation-friendly high quality, customer-focused technical content including operating procedures, maintenance procedures, technical manuals, technical illustrations, online help, and other materials as needed to support Enterprise Operations and Maintenance activities.​ Other responsibilities include, but are not limited to:


    Develop written content, technical illustrations, and photos as required for projects.​

    Obtain technical reviews from content owners and ensures the accuracy of revisions to provide customers with the highest quality technical materials.​

    Collaborate with business partners to develop and manage a technical documentation plan for each project outlining deliverables, due dates, and launch requirements.​

    Arrange and manage all relationships including quality reviews as required to meet project deliverables within established timelines to ensure an accurate delivery of technical publications to the customer.​

    Adhere to and apply styles and formats as outlined in the technical writing style guide.​

    Participate in continuous improvement of technical writing processes and systems (e.​g.​, content management) to ensure quality, compliance, and reliability of technical publications.​




The successful candidate will meet the following qualifications:


    Bachelor's degree is required, preferably in Communications, English, or a technical field.​ Extensive experience will be considered in lieu of a degree.​

    3 years or more experience as a technical writer is required.​

    Experience writing for an industrial/​manufacturing company is required.​

    Strong communication skills, including writing, editing, and proofreading is required.​

    Experience writing operating procedures, technical manuals, and/​or product-oriented documentation is required.​

    Solid knowledge of Microsoft Office suite, Adobe suite products, and similar word processing and desktop publishing tools are preferred.​

    Knowledge of fonts and typefaces is required.​

    Ability to understand, interpret, and organize technical manuals and technical data are required.​

    Experience in content management and/​or revision control systems is preferred.​

    Experience with print, web-based, and electronic delivery of documents is required.​

    Strong interpersonal skills; ability to integrate seamlessly into diverse teams.​

    Basic project management skills are preferred.​

    Database and internet-related communications and file transfer knowledge is preferred.​

    Strong computer skills and outstanding organizational ability.​

    Excellent verbal and written command of the language.​

    A personality that lends itself to leadership within a group and should be able to build and maintain relationships outside the training group.​

Apply Now


4. Job Summary

Company
    RamQuest Software, Inc
Location
    Plano, TX 75093
Industries
    Computer Software
Job Type
    Full Time
    Employee
Years of Experience
    2+​ to 5 Years
Career Level
    Experienced (Non-Manager)

Technical Writer
About the Job

RamQuest, Inc.​ is a Texas-based corporation and has served as a cornerstone in the title industry since 1991.​ RamQuest products are currently in use for title closings in all 50 states and we've enabled customers of all sizes to achieve extraordinary results by helping them apply people, processes and technology to drive business results.​  

At RamQuest, we take pride in our long-standing reputation for delivering world class business solutions to our customers.​ RamQuest is the premier provider of business solutions to title and settlement agents.​


Competing in business today is tough and we know that in addition to the industry's best solution, each of our customers need the experience we can offer as a business partner to stand with them, support them and back their business.​


RamQuest brings our entire team of title, technology and business experts to each and every customer engagement.​ Armed with hundreds of years of combined experience and the knowledge gained from thousands of unique customer implementations the entire RamQuest team is committed success.​

 

Job Description:

Assist in collecting and organizing information required for creation of user’s manuals, internal and external training materials, installation guides, proposals, webhelp and reports.​ Develop and produce accurate written documentation based on company software.​ 

 

Job Duties:  

    Analyze and interpret highly specialized technical information to compose detailed documentation and technical manuals
    Review documentation for entire project to verify validity, accuracy, completeness of content, and consistency with order, style, terminology, and client standards according to company branding requirements and templates
    Consult with other SMEs to gather required information to produce accurate and consistent documentation
    Assist others with technical interpretations and appropriate phrasing for document content
    Assist with review and development of e-learning materials and content for internal and external users by using software such as StoryLine or Articulate Studio
    Plan documentation development process and coordinates writing projects
    Ability to use and navigate webhelp software such as Adobe RoboHelp

 

Additional Information:  

    This is a direct hire opportunity with RamQuest
    We offer Health, Dental, Vision, and Life Insurance.​  Short-term/​Long-term Disability coverage, and Retirement options
    Paid vacation, paid sick, and paid company holidays
    Conveniently located in Plano, TX off of the Dallas North Tollway and Plano Parkway
    Business hours are 8am - 5pm with some flexibility
    Casual dress code

5. SoftLayer Technical Writer - Technology Evangelist
The SoftLayer Technical Evangelism team is looking to bring on technical writers that are eager to get down to the nitty gritty with technical documentation.

We are in need of people to help create new documentation as well as improving existing content. The candidate will be working with subject matter experts to extract the arcane and forge that substance into words that the rest of us can understand.

On a typical day, the candidate will...
Create and/or edit:
Workshops
Presentations
Blogs
White papers
Application Programming Interface (API) documentation

Evaluate:
Existing documentation and identify gaps
Content for accuracy
Time management skills to ensure that the candidate is able to follow through on deadlines

Expect:
To work with developers, system administrators, network engineers, marketers, and salespeople
To represent SoftLayer through their words
To work autonomously on a team of other technology enthusiasts

Preferred Qualifications:
Technical background(development, system/network administration, etc)
Marketing or sales experience

Required

    High School Diploma/GED
    At least 3 years experience in technical writing
    At least 3 years experience in cloud or Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) industry
    English: Fluent



Preferred

    Bachelor's Degree
    At least 5 years experience in technical writing
    At least 5 years experience in cloud or Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) industry



IBM is committed to creating a diverse environment and is proud to be an equal opportunity employer. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, gender, gender identity or expression, sexual orientation, national origin, genetics, disability, age, or veteran status. IBM is also committed to compliance with all fair employment practices regarding citizenship and immigration status.



Job Summary

Location
    Austin, TX 78741
Industries
    Computer/​IT Services
Job Type
    Full Time
    Temporary/​Contract/​Project
Education Level
    Associate Degree
Career Level
    Experienced (Non-Manager)
Salary
    20.​00 - 25.​00 $ /​hour
Job Reference Code
    US576JKO_178502​86

6. Seeking a Japanese Translator/Technical Writer in South Austin
About the Job
Put your Japanese speaking skills to work!



Description:



Here's a fantastic opportunity for someone with previous office experience, along with bilingual Japanese and English speaking skills.​



Kelly Services is looking for an experienced Japanese Translator/​Technical Writer for a long term contract position.​



Job description:

- Translation of day-to-day communication (specifically work-related) and technical documentation

- Consecutive and simultaneous interpreting for internal and external meetings





Job Requirements:



- Bilingual skills (Japanese and English) required



- Proficient in Microsoft Office: Excel, Word and PowerPoint



- Excellent written and verbal communication skills







Preferred Skills:



- Experience with SDL TRADOS or other translation assistance software



- Experience with structured authoring languages (XML, HTML, etc.​)




Why Kelly®?​

At Kelly Services®, we work with the best.​ Our clients include 97 of the Fortune 100™ companies, and more than 70,000 hiring managers rely on Kelly annually to access the best talent to drive their business forward.​ If you only make one career connection today, connect with Kelly.​

About Kelly Services®

Kelly Services, Inc.​ (Nasdaq: KELYA, KELYB) is a global leader in providing workforce solutions.​ Kelly® offers a comprehensive array of outsourcing and consulting services as well as world-class staffing on a temporary, temporary-to-hire, and direct-hire basis.​ Serving clients around the world, Kelly provided employment to more than 555,000 employees in 2014.​ Revenue in 2014 was $5.​6 billion.​ Visit kellyservices.​com and connect with us on Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter.​ Download WorkWire™, a free career and employment resource iPad® app by Kelly Services.​

iPad is a trademark of Apple Inc.​, registered in the U.​S.​ and other countries.​ App Store is a service mark of Apple Inc.​

Kelly Services is an equal opportunity employer including, but not limited to, Minorities, Females, Individuals with Disabilities, Protected Veterans, Sexual Orientation, Gender Identity and is committed to employing a diverse workforce.​

7. IEM Careers
IEM is an Equal Opportunity Employer (Minorities/Females/Disabled/Veterans).

Start Over with Job Search

Already have a profile?  Login Now

Proposal Writer/Coordinator
Position Type	Full-Time
 	 
Location(s):
Baton Rouge, LA
Responsibilities:

    Locations: Baton Rouge, LA or Morrisville, NC

    We’re looking for a motivated, talented individual to join our team of proposal management professionals. We’re a fast-growing company doing innovative work on the state, national, and international stage. We need people who can effectively manage proposals of all sizes through the full proposal life cycle, from the bid decision process through production and delivery.

    The successful candidate will be responsible for the following: 
        Coordinating proposal activities across a broad range of personnel, including upper-management, technical staff, editors, graphic designers, and subcontractors
        Analyzing Requests for Proposals (RFPs) to derive proposal structures and requirements
        Leading effective proposal review and strategy meetings
        Assisting and coaching technical personnel in making proposal contributions, including providing effective critiques and feedback
        Understanding and communicating the benefits of technical matter to non-technical audiences
        Developing compelling and compliant proposal content and layout
        Overseeing quality control, production, and on-time delivery of proposal documents
        Assessing personal performance, capturing lessons learned, and continuously refining proposal infrastructure and processes

     

Skills Required:

    Ability to collaborate effectively and comfortably with personnel at all levels, from technical and administrative personnel to the company president
    Strong communication skills (written and verbal), including excellent editing abilities
    Outstanding ability to organize/prioritize/schedule/coordinate
    Ability to balance detail orientation and Big Picture perspectives effectively
    Flexibility in the face of rapidly changing circumstances
    Commitment to continual process refinement and self-improvement
    Proactive engagement and willingness to take ownership of outcomes
    Strong proficiency with Microsoft Office products
    Ability to forecast and strategically plan for meetings with personnel at all levels
    Ability to translate RFPs into proposal requirements and technical features into customer benefits 

Qualifications:

    Bachelor's degree in English, Journalism, Communications, Marketing, or related field
    Experience with successful government proposal development is a plus; however, equivalent types of experience will be considered for exceptional candidates 


8. Job Description 
Technical Writer (Entry Level - 2015)-239176

Description
 

SPECIFIC RESPONSIBILITIES

 

Reviews technical drawings and develops operating instructions, maintenance instructions, and remove and replace procedures. Updates will include tools, test equipment and required personnel and support equipment. 

 

Reads and interprets contracts and specifications and determines detailed requirements. Prepares and writes technical manuals, publications, proposals and logistics support documentation.

 

Coordinates technical manual editing, composition, production, and delivery in accordance with applicable specifications, standards, and other requirements.

 

Responsible for maintaining schedule and performance control of assigned programs.

 

Coordinates the quality-control, Illustrations, production activities required to ensure the accuracy and adequacy of each publication, including in-process and final review, editing for compliance with all applicable specifications and standards, validation and change verification.

 

Participates in review conferences with customers. Provides direction to other writers and support personnel who may assist with assigned tasks.

 

Practices Total Quality principles and concepts.

Qualifications
 

BASIC REQUIREMENTS: Education

 

Typically requires a minimum of three years of related experience with a Bachelor’s Degree in a technical field to include information technology or engineering (electronics/mechanical), or equivalent education or experience to demonstrate the ability to successfully perform the job duties.

 

EXPERIENCE

 

Experience in publications development and computer information systems.  Thorough knowledge of analog and digital electronics and good mechanical aptitude. Ability to perform in-depth research - read and interpret engineering design drawings (e.g., electrical schematics, assembly drawings, wire lists, parts list, etc.). Ability to plan, organize and schedule.  Ability to document all types of equipment designs.

 

 

PREFERRED REQUIREMENTS:

 

Experience with Arbortext Epic Editor Software a plus.
Textron is committed to providing Equal Opportunity in Employment, to all applicants and employees regardless of, race, color, religion, sex, age, national origin, military status, veteran status, handicap, physical or mental disability, sexual orientation, gender identity, genetic information or any other characteristic protected by law.

Applicants selected will be subject to a government security investigation and must meet eligibility requirements, including US Citizenship, for access to classified information.

Job Field: Program Management
Primary Location: US-Maryland-Hunt Valley
Recruiting Company: Textron Systems: Support Solutions
Schedule: Full-time
Job Level: Individual Contributor
Shift: First Shift
Job Posting: 08/25/2015, 2:42:08 PM

Textron (and its subsidiaries) participates in E-Verify. We will provide the U.S. Social Security Administration (SSA) and, if necessary, the U.S. Department of Homeland Security (DHS) with information from each new employer’s Form I-9 to confirm work authorization. 


9.ICD/Test Engineer/Tech Writer 	
More Sharing Services
Share on email
Share on favorites
Share on linkedin
Share on facebook
Share on twitter
Get the CGI RSS Feed View a printer-friendly version of this page		
Category: 	Information Technology
City: 	San Diego, California, United States
Position ID: 	J0815-1766 - Permanent Full Time
Position Description:

"This position requires a SECRET clearance."

Position Summary:
CGI Federal is seeking a ICD/Test Engineer/Tech Writer position to work in our San Diego, CA location. The successful candidate will provide support to SPAWAR SSC-PAC for the SSC-PAC C4I Test and Evaluation, IV&V, and SSA Support

The Interface Control Document Engineering will collaborate with SPAWAR 5.0, Program of Record, and stakeholders across SYSCOM to develop and document boundaries, dataflow, and responsibilities between Software-to-Software, Software-to-Hardware, Hardware-to-Hardware, Hardware-to-Network, Network-to-Network and between SYSCOM-to-SYSCOM. This candidate will include in the boundaries information sufficient to outline the OSI Model Layer 1-7, to include, physical connection, ports, protocols, application, etc. The ICD engineer will assist to foster open communications with SPAWAR 5.0 leadership and system owners to validate and ensure information within the ICDs are accurately documented. The ICD documents include as-is and as-programmed platform architectures; System of System (SoS) requirements and enterprise reference architectures (i.e., the future desired platform architectures); and interface specifications, standards and profiles.

Principle Duties & Responsibilities:
- Develop and Document ICD system level diagram depictions, identifying IT TA Boundary, POR Boundary, logical path direction on physical connections, and system components, and network boundaries.
- Develop and Document ICD OSI Stack Diagrams to include Layer 1-7 -Develop and Document C4I Network Interface Diagram.
- Coordinate engineering and TA interfaces with PEOs, other SYSCOMs, the Naval Forces, DON CIO, ASN (RD&A), other Services and DoD -Support Configuration Control Board to review and adjudicate member proposed changes to the baseline IT/IA interface definitions, architectures, technical standards, specifications, etc.
- Analyze POR Interface documentation for consistency, correctness, and identify areas that provide inconsistencies.
- Develop and Maintain ICD processes, workflows, and configuration control.
- Identify Non-IP systems

Required Knowledge, Skills, & Abilities:
- 3 (MANDATORY) or 5/more (PREFERRED) years’ experience as a systems, software engineer
- IAT II Certification with Linux OS certification (current Security + certification)
- Background with PEOC4I System-of-Systems and End-to-End architecture
- Engineering/IT degree with three years of experience or five years of relevant IT experience.
- DoD Active Clearance
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills
- Ability to build consensus between Program of Records and obtain executive approval for ICDs
- Strong interpersonal and consultative skills to effectively communicate ICD requirements

Additional Requirements:
- Ability to successfully complete the CGI Background Investigation to include; 50 State Criminal, Education and Employment; Additionally, your ability to successfully complete a Credit and/or Driving Records Checks may be conducted if required by the contract for continued employment.
- Possession of an ACTIVE SECRET security clearance with a Special Clearance Investigation is required to begin employment; US Citizenship is required
- Demonstrate sufficient knowledge and experience to appropriately apply a methodology to projects that have reasonably well-defined project requirements and deliverables
- Proficient in Microsoft Office products and SharePoint
- Ability to successfully complete drug testing based on contract requirements.
- Ability to establish working relations at all organizational levels. Demonstrate ability to diplomatically and effectively deal with Government officials and program office stakeholders.
- Self-motivator with ability to work as part of a team or independently with little supervision or direction.
- Professional oral and written presentation skills.
- Attention to detail and effective problem-solving skills

Desired Knowledge, Skills, & Abilities:
- Knowledge of DAU interface management process
- Knowledge of PEOC4I Interface Control Working Group
- Thorough knowledge and experience with various Software, networking technologies, standards, and protocols
- 3 years minimum experience as network engineer
- Knowledge of cybersecurity
- 3 years experience integrating systems into CANES or ISNS
- Working knowledge with CANES and ISNS
- Experience with ExAM/ARM software suite of tools
- Experience with CMPro
- Experience with FID (functional Interface Diagram)

Education Requirement:
Bachelor's degree with 3 years of relevant experience.

At CGI, we’re a team of builders. We call our employees members because all who join CGI are building their own company - one that has grown to 68,000 professionals located in 40 countries. Founded in 1976, CGI is a leading IT and business process services firm committed to helping clients succeed. We have the global resources, expertise, stability and dedicated professionals needed to achieve results for our clients - and for our members. Come grow with us. Learn more at www.cgi.com.

This is a great opportunity to join a winning team. CGI offers a competitive compensation package with opportunities for growth and professional development. Benefits for full-time, permanent members start on the first day of employment and include a paid time-off program and profit participation and stock purchase plans.

We wish to thank all applicants for their interest and effort in applying for this position, however, only candidates selected for interviews will be contacted.

No unsolicited agency referrals please.

Qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to their race, color, religion, sex, gender Identity, sexual orientation, national origin, age, disability, veteran status, pregnancy, or other status protected by law.
Skills:

    Communication (Oral/Written)
    Configuration Management
    Detail-oriented
    Testing Environments



10. 	Maximo Technical (Java, Integrations, Configurations) Folsom, CA
	Interloc Solutions - Folsom, CA
	We have immediate needs for Maximo technical staff for projects throughout the US & Canada. Applicants must be willing to travel at rates of 100%. Interloc is interested in candidates who meet, or closely meet, the following criteria:

Essential Functions

Provide technical services over the entire lifecycle of a project
Conduct Maximo installations and upgrades
Participate in solution architecture design.
Perform application and solution development to meet project requirements
Develop and document detailed technical designs to meet business requirements
Manage multiple technical environments and support the development and testing processes
Lead or assist in data conversion and migration efforts
Configure Maximo and assist in the development of interfaces to external systems
Identify areas of customization and optimization and provide solutions that meet the business requirements
Conduct system testing as necessary
Assist users as necessary in support of go-live activities

Requirements
BS in Computer Science, Engineering or Business related field and / or equivalent work experience
Strong Maximo technical knowledge required to help execute numerous sub-projects within overall EAM Program.
Minimum five (5) years of hands-on experience in a technical position with the implementation and utilization of fully integrated enterprise asset management system
Minimum of three (3) years Maximo experience
Must be able to convert functional requirements into technical specifications, and configure, tailor and or customize the solutions including building interfaces
Ability to create and update advanced technical documentation
Must possess strong communication skills and the ability to work well in a project team environment
Must have strong project team experience with multiple successful Maximo project implementations

One (1) to five (5) years coding/development experience with:
o Interface writing
o Java / J2EE
o WebSphere
o XML
o PL SQL
o Oracle 9i or later
o Report Writers: Actuate, SQR, Crystal

Ability to lead sub-projects may be assigned.

Preferred
Maximo Certification
Maximo Integration Framework (MIF, MEA) experience

Advanced experience with:
o XML experience, including deployment of web services
o MS SQL Server.
o Visual Basic, .Net and C++.

Experience with extensions to Maximo business objects, class files, deployed web services, customizations, and configurations. The ability to determine the correct solution to the problem, not just the most attractive technically but one which will sustain the implementation is paramount 

 Maximo Technical (Java, Integrations, Configurations) Folsom, CA
Interloc Solutions - Folsom, CA
We have immediate needs for Maximo technical staff for projects throughout the US & Canada. Applicants must be willing to travel at rates of 100%. Interloc is interested in candidates who meet, or closely meet, the following criteria:

Essential Functions

Provide technical services over the entire lifecycle of a project
Conduct Maximo installations and upgrades
Participate in solution architecture design.
Perform application and solution development to meet project requirements
Develop and document detailed technical designs to meet business requirements
Manage multiple technical environments and support the development and testing processes
Lead or assist in data conversion and migration efforts
Configure Maximo and assist in the development of interfaces to external systems
Identify areas of customization and optimization and provide solutions that meet the business requirements
Conduct system testing as necessary
Assist users as necessary in support of go-live activities

Requirements
BS in Computer Science, Engineering or Business related field and / or equivalent work experience
Strong Maximo technical knowledge required to help execute numerous sub-projects within overall EAM Program.
Minimum five (5) years of hands-on experience in a technical position with the implementation and utilization of fully integrated enterprise asset management system
Minimum of three (3) years Maximo experience
Must be able to convert functional requirements into technical specifications, and configure, tailor and or customize the solutions including building interfaces
Ability to create and update advanced technical documentation
Must possess strong communication skills and the ability to work well in a project team environment
Must have strong project team experience with multiple successful Maximo project implementations

One (1) to five (5) years coding/development experience with:
o Interface writing
o Java / J2EE
o WebSphere
o XML
o PL SQL
o Oracle 9i or later
o Report Writers: Actuate, SQR, Crystal

Ability to lead sub-projects may be assigned.

Preferred
Maximo Certification
Maximo Integration Framework (MIF, MEA) experience

Advanced experience with:
o XML experience, including deployment of web services
o MS SQL Server.
o Visual Basic, .Net and C++.

Experience with extensions to Maximo business objects, class files, deployed web services, customizations, and configurations. The ability to determine the correct solution to the problem, not just the most attractive technically but one which will sustain the implementation is paramount

11.Technical Writer - Control Systems & Embedded Systems

Location:
    US-MA-Natick (Related locations: Framingham, Worcester, Metro West, Boston, Massachusetts, New England)
Job Function:
    Documentation & Editorial
Job Number:
    13949-RKUL

Job Summary

Do you have a flair for writing and a talent for explaining complex concepts to technical audiences?

Would you like to teach others how to use Simulink software to solve challenging engineering problems in diverse industries such as aerospace, automotive, and communications? 

Simulink is powerful software that enables engineers to graphically model and simulate complex systems on their computers. Engineers around the world use Simulink to get their ideas off the ground, including developing safety-critical control systems and reducing fuel emissions. Simulink add-on products have specialized components for aerospace, communications, control logic, signal processing, video and image processing, and many other applications.

You might be:

    An experienced electrical, systems, or software engineer considering a career change
    A recent graduate in engineering or computer science with a keen interest in technical communication
    An experienced technical writer with a strong engineering or computer science background

Come join a team that writes sophisticated online help content that teaches engineers and students to use our software to solve their challenging engineering problems.
Responsibilities

At MathWorks, we take pride in our documentation and it is a fully-integrated part of our software. As an important member of a multidisciplinary team, you will:

    Work with customer-facing groups and engage directly with customers to learn about the challenging, real-life engineering problems they use Simulink to solve.
    Get hands-on with our software and build the knowledge you need to write interesting, realistic tutorials, examples, and procedures for our users.
    Be an important part of our software development process. Review new features and suggest improvements. Help us design our state-of-the-art tools before we release them to customers.

Minimum Qualifications

    A bachelor's degree and 3 years of professional work experience (or a master's degree) is required.

Additional Qualifications

    Bachelors or Masters in engineering, science, mathematics, or other technical area
    Experience using MATLAB and/or Simulink
    Professional experience, preferably in a fast-paced software development environment
    Experience writing for a technical audience
    Proven ability to explain complex engineering or science concepts clearly
    Ability to work collaboratively within cross-function product teams and a multi-writer team
    Knowledge of a programming language
    Experience modeling dynamic systems

To be considered for this opportunity, please include the following information as part of your online application (when asked for Additional Documents):

    Samples of original writing that showcase your ability to convey complex procedures and concepts to technical audiences (PDFs or URLs)
    Overview of any experience using MathWorks products.

Cover letter explaining why you want to be a Technical Writer at MathWorks and what you can bring to the position.

12. Auto req ID 	13199BR
Job Title 	Documentation Developer / Technical Writer
Career Level 	Entry Level/ Junior Professional
Job Description 	Cerner’s CTS IT Strategy Team is looking for a Technical Writer. You’ll be responsible for creating, editing, and maintaining electronic content designed to communicate Cerner's IT Strategy to internal and external stakeholders. In this role you’ll gather information about the needs, objectives, business value, technologies and requirements, and translate information into cases for change, business cases, strategy documents and roadmaps.
Qualifications 	Desired Skills:
• Ability to apply advanced technical communication theory to ensure audience appropriateness, readability, and usability of content
• Ability to create standards, apply usability evaluations, testing, and possibly content research
• Knowledge of and ability to comply with documentation control procedures specified by Cerner, ISO, FDA, and other regulatory agencies as needed
• Ability to ensure accuracy, quality, and a unified style based on Cerner and industry standards
• Ability to assist in the design of documentation templates
• Ability to produce high-quality content that adheres to defined standards
• Ability to provide on-time delivery of project deliverables
• Proficiency in all tools necessary for the development and maintenance of documentation
• Ability and desire to effectively and efficiently work in a collaborative team environment
• Excellent written and oral communication skills
• Basic- to intermediate-level skills with MS Office suites
• Ability to learn and apply new technical skills and concepts quickly
• Ability to manage multiple projects simultaneously
Basic Qualifications:
• Bachelor’s degree in Technical Communication, English or a related field, or equivalent work experience
Company Overview 	Be a part of something that matters. Something that affects every single person, every single day—people’s health and the care they receive. Recognized as one of the most innovative companies in the world (#22 in 2014 by Forbes ), Cerner is transforming health care by developing tools and technologies that make it easier and more efficient for care providers and patients to navigate the complexity of our health. From single offices to entire countries, Cerner technology solutions are licensed by over 14,000 health care venues around the world.
Additional Information 	Cerner’s policy is to provide equal employment opportunity to all people without regard to race, color, religion, sex, national origin, ancestry, marital status, veteran status, age, disability, sexual orientation or gender identity or expression or any other legally protected category. Cerner is proud to be a drug-free workplace. Applicants for U.S. based positions with Cerner Corporation must be legally authorized to work in the United States. Verification of employment eligibility will be required at the time of hire. Visa sponsorship is not available for this position.

EEO is the Law (English)                                                  EEO is the Law (Spanish)
E-Verify Participation (English)                                       E-Verify Participation (Spanish)
Right to Work (English)                                                    Right to Work (Spanish)
Street Address 	10200 Abilities Way
City 	Kansas City
State/Province 	Kansas
Country 	United States
Job Function 	Technical
Administration & Operations

13. Journalist/Technical Writer/Copy Writer
Sector3 Appraisals - Providence, RI

Position: Writer/Editor
As a member of the Sector3 writing team, the writer will work closely with all levels of staff to produce content as assigned for use in Sector3 reports and publications.

This position is in our Providence office.

Major Responsibilities

    Research and write assigned reports to be used in Sector3 appraisals.
    Review/edit Sector3 appraisal reports.
    Copy edit Sector3 newsletter copy as needed.
    Keep up to date with general steel and nonferrous market trends and economic conditions through trade publications and targeted research in order to produce and develop market reports.
    Consult with appraisers, analysts and publicly available information sources to compile concise summaries of the clients’ operations, customer and supplier bases, product descriptions and major end-markets.
    Edit and proofread all assigned copy, data and graphics for grammar and style and uphold consistency throughout reports.
    Other projects as assigned.

Required Skills

    Writing/Editing Experience : College degree, with emphasis in journalism, business or technical writing and 1-3 years’ experience in technical writing or journalism. This position requires strong writing and editing skills, including proficiency in Microsoft Word and a working knowledge of Microsoft Excel. Microsoft Publisher and layout experience is a plus.
    General Business Knowledge : Strong comprehension of general business terms and concepts, and must be able to edit the writing of financial analysts and appraisers. The candidate cannot be intimidated by numbers.
    Efficiency, Flexibility & Deadline Orientation : Allocate time efficiently, balance shifting priorities with attention to deadlines and continually seek ways to improve individual and company productivity. Understands that client deadlines are often inflexible and is willing to put forth extra effort to ensure deadlines are met.
    Professional Communication Style : Ability to effectively and concisely communicate ideas. Proven ability to construct narratives, graphs and tables that summarize key findings of analysis or research. Possess the ability to succinctly explain general market and economic conditions based on research, general market knowledge and internal expertise.
    Autonomy and Accountability : Ability to remain motivated and focused on productive work activities without close supervision, yet willing to accept responsibility for the completeness and accuracy of work product within project deadlines.
    Consistent Performance and Attention to Detail : Consistently produces accurate, insightful and timely content. Applicants must have impeccable attention to detail and the ability to effectively proof their own work product and the work product of peers.
    Location: Providence, RI.

Job Type: Full-time

Required experience:

    Journalism, copy writing or technical writing: 3 years

Required education:

    Bachelor's

14.Job Description
Mindbank Job Description

Sr. Technical Writer Job Details

Job ID: 214193

Clearance: Must be able to obtain a Public Trust Clearance

Contact: [Click Here to Email Your Resumé]

Job Title: Sr. Technical Writer Salary: Up to 110,000.00 plus benefits and PTO and 401K plan

Job Type: 6 month temp  to perm

Job Start: September 2015

Type of Company: Government System Integrator

Work Location: Washington, DC

Parking: Public or Metro accessible

Attire: Business Casual - Professional

Relocation: Client is not paying for any relocation for this position

Sr. Technical Writer / User Experience Professional

Our client is an Information Technology, Web and Communications firm with 23 years of experience providing professional services to large Federal clients.

As part of the User Experience (UX) team supporting our Federal Client�s Web Program in the Office of Communications, you will be responsible for documenting and updating all web standards for the Agency and providing support on most UX projects.

Responsibilities:

� Researching, designing, writing, and editing web standards for all audiences at Federal Client�s agency � employees and executives who plan and ask for web content, content owners and subject matter experts, authors using client�s content management systems, user experience designers, and web developers � Coming up with the best ways to present all web standards to the various audiences (via the employee website) and devising the information architecture for the content � Collaborating on the user interaction design and principles for use for any special search mechanism or other UI component discussed in the standards � Through this web standards project, make it possible for all audiences to understand and meet legal requirements for web content, as well as to follow client�s standards and guidelines � Support the UX team by writing UI text and messages, performing expert reviews, documenting requirements, conducting user research, etc.

Qualifications:

Minimum Education/Experience Experience:

� Experience producing and developing Communications Plans and Requirements Documentation � for large IT Acquisition Programs. � Some formal training in human factors, cognitive psychology, usability or UX design � A minimum of 4 years of experience as part of a software development or product team with a focus on � technical writing (requirements, user stories, instructions, other documentation) � Experience documenting web standards and UX style guides, and authoring content in a content management system � Knowledge of user-centered design methodologies � Ability to multi-task and work efficiently under pressure with careful attention to detail � Self-motivated, organized, and accountable � Passion for design and eagerness to collaborate with other creative people � Strong writing portfolio

Education:

� Bachelor�s degree English, Journalism, History, Political Science, Communications, Marketing, Information Systems or equivalent degree. Experience � 8+ years of relevant work experience is required

Clearance: Must be able to obtain a Public Trust Clearance

For immediate consideration, please send your resume to: [Click Here to Email Your Resumé] Mindbank

Consulting is an equal opportunity employer. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, religion, color, national origin, gender, gender identity, age, sexual orientation, status as a protected veteran, among other things, or status as a qualified individual with a disability.

15.
Senior Scientific Writer, Toxicology - Nonclinical Writing and Documentation Job
Apply now »

Date: Aug 11, 2015

Location: Summit, New Jersey, United States
Celgene is a global biopharmaceutical company leading the way in medical innovation to help patients live longer, better lives. Our purpose as a company is to discover and develop therapies that will change the course of human health. We value our passion for patients, quest for innovation, spirit of independence and love of challenge. With a presence in more than 70 countries - and growing - we look for talented people to grow our business, advance our science and contribute to our unique culture.

1. Independently author and/or collaborate with appropriate representatives from NCD disciplines (Toxicology and Drug Metabolism & Pharmacokinetics) and Pharmacology/Translational Medicine for technical writing of reports for non-GLP exploratory toxicology studies and/or nonclinical pharmacology studies conducted within Celgene Translational Development or Experimental Toxicology/Therapeutics and/or by external collaborators.
2. Work with Regulatory Operations department and NWD Document Specialists to maintain the electronic study report repository, and manage the Author, Review, and Approval process for electronic submission documents.
3. Represent NCD Toxicology functions on submission teams and in collaboration with functional leads to devise and implement the strategy for document preparation as per timelines agreed upon by the functions and submission team.
4. Review data to determine the appropriate tabular and textual formats, and the clarity, logic and order of presentation.
5. Be an expert user of the templates for nonclinical documents that are consistent with FDA and ICH guidelines and with electronic submissions guidelines.
6. Facilitate document review meetings, resolution meetings, and discussions as needed pertaining to comment resolution leading to the on-time completion of a high quality document.
7. As needed, review work of other writers (in-house or contract) for accuracy, quality, focus, and adherence to format, and stylistic requirements in order to ensure high quality documents are produced within the NWD Function.
8. Examine existing NWD procedures and make recommendations to enhance NWD policies and procedure, internal document controls, and work practices to improve overall NCD document quality.
9. Other duties as assigned

*LI-KM1
J2W:PR

Qualifications
Prerequisite:

Advanced degree in biological/toxicological or related sciences (MS or PhD) with 3 to 5 years of professional scientific writing experience

Skills/Knowledge Required:
• Advanced degree in biological/toxicological or related sciences (MS or PhD) with 3 to 5 years of professional scientific writing experience.
• Must have experience as a nonclinical toxicology, pharmacokinetics, and/or pharmacology writer that included contributions to Investigational New Drug (IND), New Drug Application (NDA), and/or Common Technical Documents (CTD) and electronic document submissions (eCTD) for Food and Drug Administration (FDA) submissions, and nonclinical & regulatory documents included in registration dossiers for worldwide use.
• Familiarity with toxicology, in vivo animal studies, pharmacokinetics, pharmacology, cell biology, and biochemistry required.
• Knowledgeable in nonclinical drug development process including good laboratory practices (GLP) toxicology and safety pharmacology IND enabling studies.
• Knowledge of the FDA and ICH guidelines pertaining to new chemical entity development and regulatory submissions to global health authorities.
• Excellent scientific writing and verbal communication skills. Demonstrated ability to compile concise summaries of complicated data sets.
• Proficient in use of Microsoft Word, Excel, data graphics software, Adobe Acrobat, and web-based browser software such as LiveLink to manage electronic document authoring, reviewing, and approval process.
• Ability to work with multiple complex projects and within cross-functional teams.

Celgene is committed to equal opportunity in the terms and conditions of employment for all employees and job applicants without regard to race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, age, gender identity or gender expression, national origin, disability or veteran status.

Celgene complies with all applicable national, state and local laws governing nondiscrimination in employment as well as employment eligibility verification requirements of the Immigration and Nationality Act. All applicants must have authorization to work for Celgene in the U.S.
.

Req ID: 15001089
Primary Location: United States-New Jersey-Summit
Job: Research and Development
Organization: Celgene Corporation
Schedule: Regular
Shift: Standard
Employee Status: Individual Contributor
Job Type: Full-time
Job Level: Day Job
Travel: Yes, 5 % of the Time
Job Posting: 2015-05-16 00:00:00.0


Nearest Major Market: New Jersey
Job Segment: Chemistry, Biochemistry, Scientific, Toxicology, Chemical Research, Science, Engineering
